Tommaso Mario Buonocore

Biomedical Engineer

Summary

Biomedical Engineer and AI enthusiast, currently researching NLP solutions to improve healthcare-based prediction tasks leveraging Italian clinical notes.

Geek, musician, bicycle lover. I embrace social and environmental sustainability to support more fair, responsible and ethical relations with the planet and its humans.

Work experience

Software Engineer & NLP Consultant

02/2021 - today

Biomeris S.r.l. - Pavia (IT)

Working on Shiny R web application for OMOP data visualization. Helping with NLP-related activities.

PhD Student - Big Data and Biomedical Informatics

10/2020 - today

University of Pavia & ICS Maugeri - Pavia (IT)

Currently researching NLP techniques to improve patient representation learning and classification with Italian biomedical language models.

Teacher of the Advanced Machine Learning course (NLP section) for Master's students. Collaborating with ICS Maugeri, ICCU Monzino, and other medical institutes.

Machine Learning Engineer

07/2019 - 04/2020

Academisch Medisch Centrum - Amsterdam (NL)

Worked on fall prevention in elderly patients, implementing a support system based on discrete Bayesian networks.

Researched Natural Language Processing methods (word embeddings, language models) applied to freetext clinical notes.

Software Engineer (Internship)

05/2019 - 07/2019

Biomeris S.r.l. - Pavia (IT)

Worked on software modules for Diagnostic Therapeutic Care Pathway management for Multiple Sclerosis.

Machine Learning Engineer (Internship)

10/2018 - 03/2019

Academisch Medisch Centrum - Amsterdam (NL)

Researched NLP models for the early detection of colorectal cancer leveraging EHR unstructured data.

Software Engineer (Internship)

04/2016 - 09/2016

Biomeris S.r.l. - Pavia (IT)

Worked on a JavaScript library for genograms' representation and visualization.

Education

Master's Degree in Biomedical Engineering

09/2016 - 07/2019

110/110 Cum Laude - University of Pavia

Courses: Advanced Biomedical Machine Learning (30/30), Medical Informatics (30L/30), Data Mining and Clinical Decision Support (30/30), Telemedicine (29/30), Information Security (30/30), Biomathematics (28/30), Artificial Intelligence in Medicine (28/30).

Bachelor's Degree in Biomedical Engineering

09/2012 - 04/2016

100/110 - University of Pavia

Music Studies 2004 - 2010

Higher Institute of Music Studies F. Vittadini, Pavia

Volunteer Experience

Collaborator & Content Creator

2021 - today

ComIntAr

ComIntArt is an Italian group that follows the 'popular science' approach to provide Artificial Intelligence contents to the general audience.

Technical Writer 2019 - today

Towards Data Science

Writing about Data Science, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence and Programming for one of the most popular data science blogs in the world.

Contributions: https://medium.com/@detsutut

Translator 2019 - 2020

Coursera

Helping making up for the lack of Al-related content for non-english speakers.

Soft Skills

Patience - Critical Thinking - Perseverance Curiosity - Visual Communication - Creativity Public Speaking - Self Monitoring - Flexibility Negotiation - Cooperation - Positive Attitude

Technical Skills

Machine Learning - Deep Learning - R - Shiny Data Mining - Data Visualization - Python SQL - Medical Informatics - HTML - CSS Javascript - Natural Language Processing Matlab - Healthcare Systems - Java - Big Data

Portfolio

Projects I developed and mantained involving Data Science, Programming and Analytics. Source codes are available on GitHub.



Sinapsi

Web application designed to provide an easy connection between Italian family doctors and psychologists.



Chroma

Data viz R package for analyzing and exploring colors and chromatic storytelling in any local video source



ShinyDBNet

Shiny R Web Application designed for Discrete Bayesian Networks handling and reasoning.



MOGE

Cross-platform Mobile Application to classify cardiomyopathies according to MOGE(S) nosology system.

Certifications

Professional License - Information Engineer State exam for certification: 06/2021

Languages

Italian

Native speaker

English

Duringer fluent

Business fluent